Thank you
谢谢
I think my job today is to introduce to new ways of thinking the new concepts so I thought I'd start you off with the picture right.
我今天的主题就是向大家介绍一种对新理念的新的思考方式，我将从一张图片开始介绍
This is from... and I'm hoping this will work
这张图片拍摄于... 希望这个图片能够显示出来
This mounting here is called xxxxtripping????
这座山叫????
About two or three people died on it every year
每年都会了两到三人遇险
Partly because they don't take it seriously, it's only just 3000 feet. yeah
部分是因为这座山只有3000英尺高，没有引起游客重视
But that's a territory I'm going to come back and reference that in a minute but that's kind like where I grew up that's what I feel at home
但这是我还想再去的地方，这里给了我家的感觉，就好像我在这长大似的。
now which is another concept that I'm going to come to
接下来会有另外一个理念
Now what I want to do today is to introduce some new ways of thinking some new ideas to move things forward
今天的主题就是向大家介绍一种将事情向前推进的新的思考方式。
I want to start off by some thoughts on language
我想从我在语言上的想法开始
You may or may not have grown up with Winnie the Pooh if you're British you did
如果你在英国长大，你可能或者不是看着小熊维尼长大。
And you find the Disney version quite a appalling right
然后你发现迪士尼版本令人震惊
But there's a whole sort of structural trope which goes on on the web of people using Winnie the Pooh pictures with favorite sayings
对那些喜欢用小熊维尼作为网页头像的人来说，存在某些比喻
And you look at both of these, right you have to be a Star Trek fan to understand the second
你已经看过这两张图片了，对吧？只有星际迷航的粉丝才能理解第二幅图片
The reference to the episode of Monk and the use of metaphor
参考Monk的插曲和隐喻的使用
We use very complex metaphors to explain various complex ideas in Simple Words
我们用仅几个词但非常复杂的隐喻去解释复杂的意思
Also language change is very very quickly if you look at the left-hand one
同时如果你看左边这张图，你会发现语言发展非常非常之快
It's almost getting out of date now because the level of stupidity is gone even before above that alright or below that
这几乎都已经要过时了，因为现在糊涂程度正在发生变化
But the actual context of that and the subtlety of all the messages and all the stories that lie behind it
隐藏在后面的微妙的上下文信息及所有的故事
Goes way beyond traditional methods of codification
发展的方向都与传统的编写手法相去甚远
So I can start think about language a bit and this goes back to a quote from the philosopher Martin heidegger
因而我能够从语言开始，并回到哲学家 马丁-海德格尔的一句名言
I'm sorry about this but when he was writing I should I can't change his language to say woman and man or whatever but he basically said
很抱歉用语中男人和女人的区分，但是当他写下这句话时我没法改变他的用语
Man thinks he's a master of language but actually language is the master of Man
人类以为自己掌控着语言，但事实是语言掌控着人类
And the important thing to realise is the language you speak
重要的是你所说的语言
Largely determines how you see the world
扩展了你所认识的世界
Yeah I'm getting the language right is there for key
这正是我学习正确语言的关键
And it isn't just the fact that my first degree in physics and philosophy joint honours
不仅仅是我的物理学和哲学学士学位联合荣誉这一事实
Which give me a Desire for simplicity and purpose in beauty and lots of the stuff
它让我学会渴望简单，追求美好及很多
And language is actually quite important
语言在其中发挥的作用非常重要
Now in order to fully understand this what I want to do is come back to this particular picture
为了弄明白我所说的，让我们看一下这张图片
Yeah and start to think about a couple of things
并且想象一些事情
First of all I want to make a distinction between sense-making with a hyphen
首先我想区分一下意识构建和
And sensemaking as one word in the original
和构建意识
For those of you are familiar with calverts working if you haven't read that I recommend it
对那些熟悉卡尔弗特工作的人，如果你还没有读过那我推荐你读一下
He talks about sensemaking
他谈到了构建意识
But it comes from an academic tradition where you study cases
但在学习时他采用的的是学术解释
I'm from cases you derive Theory you should all be better to be fully familiar with that
你通过案例得出理论你应该更好地完全熟悉它
It's an empirical approach
这是一种经验方法
Sensemaking which is myself climbing others comes from a different perspective
我在其他人的不同观点基础之上，解释构建意识
It says what do we know from natural science
它介绍的是我们所知道的自然科学的知识
And how do we apply natural science to human systems
以及我们如何将自然科学应用到人类系统
And use that to create a different level of certainty
并且以此来找到它的确定性
The reason we do that is natural science can replicate his experiments
我们这么做是因为自然科学可以进行经验复用
Social science can't
社会科学却不行
And I'll come back and validate that in a minute just come make a background of the key distinction
我一会回来介绍验证，我们将了解关键区别的背景
The next key distinction I make which is not used to efficiently
我识别出的下一个关键区别是不习惯有效
It's between typologies and taxonomies
介于类型学与分类学
Data taxonomy people are familiar with we liked put things into categories
数据分类人员熟悉我们喜欢将事物分类
The problem is that in English taxonomy rhymes with taxidermy
问题在于英语中分类学与动物标本押韵
And produces very similar results
从而产生非常相似的结果
Over rigid structures in which the boundary conditions become very dangerous
在刚性结构中越界是非常危险的事情
Because you make things fit into space even if they don't
因为这样你会把原本不能放进去的物体放进这个空间里面去
I'm a typology on the other hand is a way of looking at things from different perspectives
一个类型学家会从另外一个不同的角度来看待
Now I'm going to be mainly today talking about typologies
我今天主要谈论类型学家
Looking at things from different perspectives to actually make sense of the world
从另外一个不同的角度看待事物，从而让世界符合认知
rather than try and create rigid classifications
而不是尝试创建一个死板的分类
And then we get into the stuff we were talking about in the bar last night
然后接下来会开始谈论昨天在酒吧讨论的
Which is the whole issue of map Models and frameworks
关于整个地图模型和框架所存在的问题
And he's often get conflated or confused
他经常变得混乱或困惑
So I'll give you my basic distinctions at the moment yeah
我接下来给大家介绍基本的区别
A model seeks to represent the world
用模型表达世界
I'm going to come back later from a complexity perspective
我稍后会回来从复杂性角度介绍
And quote Murray gell-mann The only valid model of a human system is the system itself
引用默里格尔曼的观点，唯一能够验证人类系统的模型就是人类系统本身
Now that starts to give us problems
现在给我们带来了一些麻烦
A model seeks to represent the world and we see this a lot in systems architecture in elsewhere
一个想要表达全世界的模型，我们在很多系统架构中都看到了
And then people work within the model framework
人们借助模型进行工作
But the trouble is there are limits to the application of models
但问题是应用模型是有局限的
It doesn't mean they're not useful but we need to be careful
这并不是说模型没有用，而是应该小心使用
A framework on the other hand is generally a typology
换句话说框架是一门类型学
It's a way of looking at things from different perspectives so you can make distinctions
这是一种从不同角度看事物的方式，因此你可以做出区分
And therefore by those making distinctions do things in different ways
因此，做出区分后就会以不同的方式做事
And then a map gives you somewhere placing yourself of understanding where you are
一份图示可以帮助你认识自己理解到了什么程度
So this is the actual map of the area that you show the picture of earlier, this is the Nun frakkin egwin Valley this ribbon
所以这是你所展示的早期图片的实际地图
You can see a bit, now that's a 1:25000 scale map
你能看到一些，这是张地图是1:25000
It's a really good planning map you're not going to make any major mistakes on that
这是一个非常好的规划图，你不会在那里犯任何重大错误
That you can see the tracks you can see the contour lines
你可以看到轨迹和轮廓线
Now most of us if we're walking there use Harvey maps Which work on  1:40000 scale
现在我们走去那里都会使用Harvey地图，这些地图的工作范围比例尺是1：40000
If you actually look at that that's been designed very specifically for walkers
如果你仔细的看那个专为步行者设计的地图
It's got much more detail on it you can actually see where there a cliff somewhere there aren't
你能从中获得更多的信息，包括悬崖在哪
The golden rule if you have a walk on the way， if you get lost， stay to the crest
在你迷路的情况下，黄金法则就是朝着波峰走去
It may be scary but you won't die
这可能很可怕，但你不会死
If you try and take a short cut you'll die right in terms of cliff
在悬崖边如果你试着走捷径，你就会死
And of course no matter how familiar you are with Maps you can make mistakes the danger with Maps as you become overconfident
当然无论你对地图多么熟悉，如果过于自信都会犯危险的错误
We don't read them again we see forward If I go back to roughly this time. last year I made exactly that mistake on the top of tripping
如果我再回那我会向前看不再仔细看地图。去年我在绊倒之前犯了这个错误
with that net result in 8 stitches yeah
产生的后果就是缝了8针
So Maps don't design that should never taken a selfie. the family never forgave me for that
所以地图不会设计说不应该自拍，家庭从来没有原谅我
I said I realised it was bad I fell over on the top and I walked down the field I'll just take a picture before I wash my head
我说我意识到这很糟糕。 我在上面跌倒，然后走下了田野。 在我洗头之前，拍了一张照片
Go and give a lecture at the university
去大学做演讲
And took the picture and realise oh my god I'm gonna have to go to hospital
我拍下照片，并意识到我将不得不去医院
And then the perfect tweet came to mind. Red door on tripping so that kept me going to the bottom because I really wanted
然后想到了完美的推文。 旅途上有个红色的门通往山底
The tweet with the picture
推文可以配张图
And shall we say cause some problems
我们应该说会引起一些问题
The point is that Maps give you a starting point but you still got to be careful and familiarity breeds contempt
地图给你一个起点，但你仍然要小心, 对熟悉的内容反而会引起蔑视轻视
I'm trying to create some basic language at the moment
我正在尝试创建一些基本语言
The other points and this is one of the biggest issues I see with architecture and elsewhere this is from an Mount Pendleton
另外一点这是我在架构中看到的最大问题之一，而在其他地方，这是来自彭德尔顿山xxxx
Julian a good friend of mine and she's currently actually just about to publish a new book with John Seely Brown on design
我的一位好朋友Julian目前正准备与John Seely Brown合作出版一本关于设计的新书
Working with us on an complexity approach to design thinking with Stanford University
与Stanford大学合作的关于进行设计思维的复杂方法
I may come back to that a bit later
我稍后可能会再回过头来
She says and this is a critical point the whole point about scaffolding is you take it away when you've completed the building
她说到一个关键点脚手架的重点在于构建完后可以去掉它
Get the scaffolding isn't the endpoint it's a means to an end
搭建脚手架不是终点只是达到目的的手段
one of things I see far too much within the whole of the IT industry
在整个IT行业中我看到了太多这样的事情
Is a focus on scaffolding as the end
把脚手架作为结果
In fact often it's the way the truth and the life
事实上这往往是真理和生活方式
Yet methods are elevated to the level of religion
然而方法被提升到宗教
Yeah I need a allergy in terms of the way it works
我需要对它的工作方式保持敏感
Has somebody's just launched a new approach to business agility
有人提出了业务敏捷方法
And guess what the approach is a two-day course with a certificate at the end of it
猜猜怎样，两天的课程后会颁发一个证书
That's a level of trivialization we're now getting to
这是我们现在要达到的平凡程度
So understanding that is key the other thing to
因此理解这个的另一个关键是
realize is that there are no recipes
认识到这没有指南
I'm going to justify this more as I come onto complexity
遇到复杂性时我会更好地证明这一点
And I want to make a key distinction between a recipe book user and a chef
我想在按照食谱做饭的人和厨师之间做出重要区分
A recipe book user follow the recipe
人们按照食谱制作
If I have all the right equipment and all the right ingredients there's no problem it works
如果我拥有所有合适的设备和所有正确的配料，那么它就没有问题
But if anything goes wrong
但如果出现任何偏差
They haven't got the ability the resilience to adjust
他们没有能力调整调整
A chef on the other hand can make a brilliant meal with whatever they have to hand
另一方面，厨师可以随心所欲地做出精彩的一餐
And the reason is they have two types of knowledge would Aristotle called phronesis and Sophia
原因是他们有两种类型的知识，亚里士多德称为精明和智慧
They have the theoretical knowledge of taste
他们有理论知识倾向
And the practical knowledge about apprenticeship
学徒式的实践知识
And it's the combination of 4 or 5 years of apprenticeship
这是4年或5年学徒期的结合
With deep Theoretical knowledge about the nature of food
对食物的本质有深刻的理论知识
It's the combination which gives them resilient it's not one or the other
厨师组合使它们具有特性，既不是这一个或也不是另一个
And at the moment we turn people to argue for theory or practice or practice of a theory
目前我们转向争论理论本身是实践或理论实践
And that's a mistake we need to build more chefs and fewer recipe book uses
这是一个错误，我们需要培养更多的厨师和更少的食谱书使用
So I want to do is to go through three basic bits of Science and then start to apply them
所以我想要介绍三个基本的科学，然后开始应用它们
First is the reality of the way that human beings perceive things
首先是人类感知事物的真实的方式
A second thing is how do we create novelty this is going to be really important
第二个很重要的是我们如何创造新奇
Because we try and remove accidents in system design
因为我们尝试消除系统设计中的事故
When actually in the history of evolution accidents of the most important thing
事实上事故在演进过程中扮演最重要的事故角色
It's called serendipity if you want the English language word for it
如果用英语词语表达那就是‘意外发现’
I'll go through that again finally
我们最后再过一遍
We can't predict your model and that's what I introduce complexity theory and runs for the Keynesian framework
我们无法预测您的模型，这就是我为凯恩斯主义框架引入复杂性理论和运行的内容
For the first in terms of perception
首先是感知方面
And this experiment which is been repeated many times
这个实验已多次重复
If anybody comes to you and says I've done for a pi projects let me tell you from my experience this is what you should do
如果有人来找你并说我做了四到五个项目让我告诉你通过我的经验这该怎么做
They really don't understand the Core Science
他们真的不了解核心科学
If they do three projects which partly succeed and create a worldwide method and accreditation scheme on it
如果他们做了三个部分成功的项目，并基于此上创建了一个全球性知名的方法和认证计划
And that's called snake oil salesman and charlatan
这就是所谓的蛇油推销员和骗子
And there's a lot of them around at the moment
目前他们周围有很多人
Fundamentally if you give a batch of radiologists， Now remember radiologists are coming off of 4 to 5 generation body of knowledge
从根本上说，如果你选出一批放射科医生，放射科医师正掌握着第4或5代身体知识
This is important to realise architecture it's probably a 3 generation body of knowledge
很重要的是要理解架构可能是3代知识体系
Doctors are a 5000 generation body of knowledge
医生掌握第5000代知识体系
As more generations build knowledge, practice gets built into the processes the training
随着更多代人建立知识，实践被纳入培训过程
You got more reliabilit
你能得到更高的可靠性
That's a radiologist have a full five generation body of knowledge
拥有完整的五代知识体系的放射性医生
are dealing with the limited information set
正在处理有限的信息集
Yeah in a controlled environment and most of them I got 10 or 15 years training
大多数人在受控制的环境中接受了10年或15年的培训
If you give them a batch of X-rays and ask them to look for anomalies
如果你让他们查看一批X射线并要求他们寻找异常
On  one of the x-rays you hide a picture of a gorilla which is 48 times the size of an average cancer nodule
在其中一张X光后隐藏一只大猩猩的照片，它是普通癌症结节的48倍
83% don't see it
83%的放射科医生没有看见它
Even though the right physically scanner
即使是正确的物理扫描仪
We do not see What we do not intend to see
我们看不见我们不想看的内容
We actually only see what we expect to see
我们事实只看见我们期望看见的
And the scary thing is the 17% to do see it  come to believe they were wrong
可怕的是17％的看到的人以为自己错了
When they talk with the others
当他们与其他人交谈时
Alright now that one slide undermines any approach
现在一张幻灯片打破了
Based on anybody observing what other People do
基于任何观察其他人行为的方法
Because if you're an academic or a consultant to you going steady companies
因为如果你是一名学者或顾问，你会去稳定的公司
You only see what you expect to see
你只能看到你期望看到的东西
That's just life
这只是生活
It's called confirmation bias in attentional bias in Inception
它在Inception中被称为注意力偏见中的确认偏差
Such Simon is being berating management textbooks most of this week
本周西蒙一直在抨击管理教科书
I'm quite pleased about this I normally the nasty going the internet is now becoming even nastier so that's good news
我对此感到非常高兴, 我讨厌互联网现在变得更加肮脏，所以这是个好消息
Except I think he's been generous.  I haven't yet seen a single popular management textbook Which actually didn't Commit This fundamental error
除了我认为他大度. 我还没有看到一个流行的管理教科书犯这个样的基本错误
Yeah they go and observe things, the interview people
他们观察事物，采访人物
They believe what people say when they're interviewed inform that they construct method
他们相信人们在接受采访时所说的话会能够帮助他们形成方法论
The good news on this is there's a huge amount there at to be discovered
这样做的好消息是有大量的东西需要发现
If we architect systems in the right way
如果我们以正确的方式架构系统
But we won't know What we need until we discover it
但是在发现之前我们不会知道我们需要什么
It is the the second thing key aspects from evolutionary biology
这是生物进化学的第二个关键方面\
This is called exaptation
这被称为exaptation
I know we had a general problem with creationist will we still have a problem in the states which is growing right
我知道我们与创造论者有一个普遍的问题，我们仍然会在正在成长的国家遇到问题
We thought we'd eliminated that's everything and I think is now 52% of people in the United States believe the world was created in the last 6000 years
我们认为我们已经消除了这一切，现在52％的美国人认为这个世界是在过去的6000年里创造的
Which is really scary
这真的很可怕
I'm doing work with Ebola management teams in Dallas
我正在与在达拉斯的埃博拉管理团队合作
And I was told I couldn't talk about evolution because it's a controversial Theory
我被告知我不能谈论关于进化，因为它是一个有争议的理论
And that's it your Ebola management teams, all right this gets really scary
这就是你的埃博拉管理团队，这真非常可怕
Yeah but we did have a general problem with it because there isn't enough time in the evolutionary timescale
但我们确实遇到了一个普遍的问题，因为在进化时间表上没有足够的时间
The human intelligence to have evolved
人类智慧已经发展
On a linear basis it just won't work
线性思维已经行不通
The other side of crude Neo-darwinian night near darwinian ISM
The other side of crude Neo-darwinian night near darwinian ISM
A people like Richard Dawkins in the light<>
像理查德道金斯这样的人
with its linear approach it's causal approach actually just doesn't work we got a problem
利用线性思维形成的方法无法工作，会遇到问题
Then with Robin Hood linksmi Gorgon others we discovered a thing called acceptation
Then with Robin Hood linksmi Gorgon others we discovered a thing called acceptation
two illustration of that
two illustration of that
Dinosaurs feathers evolved for warmth we can see it in the fossil record
恐龙的羽毛是为了温暖而进化而来的，我们可以在化石记录中看到它
It's over a long period of time
这会经历很长一段时间
Yeah it's kind of like Dinosaurs with no feathers or warmer
温血的恐龙没有羽毛
Therefore they survive more to breed that's a classic adaptation linear process
因此，他们繁殖生存符合经典的适应线性过程
And then by luck and it turns out the actual evolution isn't survival of the fittest. it's survivor the luckiest
然后事实证明，实际的进化并不是适者生存，幸存者是最幸运的
Something into that in Darwin's notebooks but he says this is too going too far so decide not to say it
在达尔文的笔记本中有些东西他认为这不好解释，所以决定不去说
Is that to be true
这是真的吗?
there's an arboreal species of dinosaurs because it's cold at the top of tree so you get more feathers
对于树顶的恐龙物种，因为树顶很冷所会长出更多的羽毛
But you also fall from trees
但你还是从树上掉下来了
Which means you learn to fly Actually flight is a nonlinear
这意味着你学飞行实际上是非线性的
Acceptation
Acceptation
A trait which evolved for one function and the stress
为一种特长和面对压力而演变的特质
Exit through different functions
退化不同的能力
I couldn't handle anyway because if dinosaurs threw themselves off trees in the hope of evolving feathers before they hit the ground
我无论如何无法处理，恐龙将自己扔在下树，并希望在落地之前进化出羽毛
The timescale for breeding is very short and the consequences are quite dangerous
繁殖的时间表非常短，后果非常危险
of course once you've got acceptation you get adaptation
当然，一旦你接受了，你就会适应
I was tracked by the bikes not so many months ago
不久的几个月前我自行车被跟踪了
By a tawny owl who actually literally followed me from mild and a bit of queues it was fascinating experience at dusk
排队时被一只黄褐色的猫头鹰温和的跟踪，这是黄昏时的迷人体验
And you can't hear an owl fly
你听不到猫头鹰的飞翔声
Because of feathers have involved silence that's just literally can't hear them absolutely silent flight
因为羽毛的轻柔所以绝对不会听到它们
So after accepting you get adaptation
所以在接受后你会适应
But the adaptation is based on where it started
但适应是基于它从哪里开始
There's any design in this the starting point determines the path way forwards
在这方面有任何设计，起点决定了前进的道路
You should stop at the scene where I'm going with some of the stuff now
你现在应该停下来我现在要去的地方
At the other one I love it's a cerebellum at the base of your brain evolved to manipulate muscles in fingers
另一个我喜欢的是，你大脑底部的小脑进化到能操纵手指的肌肉
It accepts in humans to manage the control of grammar in language
它支持人类在语言中进行语法控制
So huge sophistication of human language
人类语言的巨大复杂性
was a radical repurposing not a linear adaptation
是一种激进的再利用，而非线性适应
If you don't think that's relevant
如果你认为这是不相关的
Then look at what connects the magneto of a radar machine
然后看看雷达的磁发电机，
A Hershey bar and a microwave oven
好时巧克力棒与微波炉的联系
In 1945 a racing engineer
1945年一名赛车工程师
Maintaining the Magneto of a ride-on machine noticed that a chocolate bar melted in the pocket
维护磁发电机注意到巧克力棒在口袋中融化
Now 99 out of 100 engineers you notice this would swear and have their trousers cleaned
你会发现99%的工程师会发誓要清理裤子
This guy realises significance
这家伙意识到了重要性
And we got microwave ovens
于是我们有微波炉
If you look at the history of technology
如果你看一下技术史
It's a history of exaptive moments a radical repurposing
这是一个充满活力的历史，是一个不断的重新定位
Some of the stuff I'll talk about in the strategy session with Simon later on this afternoon
我将在今天下午晚些时候与西蒙一起的战略会议中一些内容
Is if you look at it you get first mover advantage by repurposing existing technology for novel purpose
讨论的是如果你能看到新颖的目的，你可以通过重新利用现有技术获得先发优势
IBM does it with punch cards
IBM通过打孔计算机做到了
Microsoft does it with software developer for IBM
微软通过为IBM进行软件开发做到了
An apple does it with next after next went bankrupt
苹果公司通过一次又一次的破产做到了
Get the radical evolution of a new apex predator
激进演变成新的顶尖捕食者
Is generally based on radical repurposing of an existing technology
通常基于对现有技术的彻底重新利用
Under conditions of stress
在存在压力的情况下
Who won the big things when they're starting to work on in terms of Architecture and design
会获得巨大收益当他们开始从事架构和设计工作
Is how do you design for serendipity
你是如何设计偶然性的
Serendipity is a wonderful English word it comes from Earth
意外发现是地球的上最精彩的英语单词
Ancient I think Italian story retold by Walpole
Ancient I think Italian story retold by Walpole
About the Two Princes Of serendipity Who get sent on quests
关于两个被派遣秘密任务的王子的意外发现
And they never found what they were looking for
他们从未找到他们想要的东西
But they find more useful things instead
但他们发现更多有用的东西
That and that's called serendipity
这就是所谓的意外发现
And reality is human invention human inside human understanding
现实是人类在人类理解中发明的人类
Is generally accepted not additive
这基本被接受而不是附加的
But that architectural structures tend to be drawn from engineering diagrams
但建筑结构往往来自工程图
Not from ecosystem
而不是生态系统
That's the big thing I'm going to start to argue for
这是我要开始争辩的重要事情
Need to start to think about human systems is a complex psychology
需要开始思考人类系统是一种复杂的心理学
Not a something which can be reduced to an engineering diagram
不是可以简化为工程图的东西
Because that reduces much of the richness
因为这减少了很多丰富性
It's leads me onto complexity
它引出了复杂性
I need a some of the most misused words that we know about
我需要一些我们所知道的最误用的词
Complexity is a knotty problem and people use complex and complicated in the same way
复杂性是一个棘手的问题，人们把繁杂和复杂等同
And people make statements like they want to reduce complexity
人们会说希望降低复杂性
And I'm sorry about this for future speaker but complexity doesn't fail
And I'm sorry about this for future speaker but complexity doesn't fail
The nature of a complex system is it always fails
复杂系统的本质是它始终失败
Now again
再重复一遍
The failure is actually quite important and I'll come back and describe that
失败实际上非常重要，我会再回来描述介绍一下
When you architect the complex system you design it for early failure
当你架构一个复杂系统时，你应该设计早期失败
Big is only through of your failure could you discover what's possible anyway
只有通过你的失败，你才能发现什么是可能的
So let me go through and build on this now build a canary in French
让我现在用法语建立一个金丝雀xxxx
So basically we have three types of system in nature, ordered systems, complex systems and chaotic systems
所以基本上我们有三种类型的系统, 有序系统, 复杂系统和混沌系统
I'm going to define these in terms of constraints
我将根据约束来定义这些
An ordered system is highly constrained
有序系统受到严格限制
There's very little degree of freedom is very little ability for anything to do anything outside The rules
几乎没有什么自由度，几乎没有事情在规则之外
That you don't see these in nature by the way then work more less unique to human beings
你没有在自然界中看到这些，但对人类来说没那么独特
An example I often give is an operating theatre
我经常举手术室的例子
In an operating theatre we now count the number of surgical instruments left at the end of an operation
在手术室中，我们计算在手术结束时留下的手术器械的数量
And jackets the same as were there at the start
以及外套的数量，必须跟手术前相同
Yeah as I get older I think this sort of stuff is of increasing importance
随着年龄的增长，我认为这种东西越来越重要
Yeah I know how many people had to have a second operation because surgical instruments will left in the body
我知道不少人必须进行第二次手术，是因为手术器械遗留在体内
That is actually over 10% on average across the world before the checklist were introduced
在核对清单出台之前，全世界的平均超过了10％
If you ever been into an operating theatre it's pretty goddamn messy it's easy to lose things alright
如果你曾经去过一个手术室，那真的很混乱，很容易遗忘东西
And the trouble is that losing things inside somebody's body
麻烦的是把东西遗忘在了人体内
Has major consequences yes the order is good
有重大影响的场景下，有序是好的
But the cost of that is high
但是成本很高
When a doctor or a nurse goes into an operating theatre anybody been into an operating theatre vertically
所有医生或护士进入手术室时都会垂直是直立的进入手术室
I've been in once horizontally in twice vertically alright and I almost got divorced I need to the vertical locations
我有一次躺着，两次直立进手术室。我差点离婚。我需要站着。
occasions my two children were both to quote William Shakespeare from their mother's womb untimely ripped
莎士比亚说我他的两个孩子从母亲肚子出生时都是历经磨难
Said it was Cesarean section
也就是剖腹产
The trouble is I grew up in a veterinary household with animals being detected on the kitchen table over breakfast
问题是我在一个兽医家庭长大，早餐时在厨房的桌子上发现了动物
So from my point for your Cesarean section was a really interesting operation and can I look more closely
从我的角度看待的这个剖腹产手术会是一个非常有趣的手术，我可以更仔细地观察
And I forgot that was meant to be there for the purposes
我会忘了那是为了这个目的而存在的
But either way if you go to into the operating theatre you go through some elaborate ritual of washing up
但无论哪种方式，如果你去进手术室要经历精细的清洗步骤
What that does Is？ it's a ritual cognitive activation is what ritual does for humans
这是什么？这是一种认知激活对人类的作用
It aligns the individual To the role that they are occupied
它使个体与他们的角色保持一致
The reason you don't see what you don't expect to see is at best your scanning 3% of what's in front of you
您没有看到您不希望看到的内容的原因充其量是您扫描前面3％的内容
And matching it against dominant patterns based on recent experience
并根据最近的经验将其与自己主导的模式相匹配
What ritual does is to change their patterns
什么仪式改变他们的模式?
So you see the world differently
所以你对世界的看法不同
We are playing with experiments with software testers
我们正在和软件测试人员做实验
I'm getting them to change clothes before they test their code
我让他们在测试代码之前换衣服
Because you actually want me to have a different cognitive activation pattern
你实际上希望我拥有不同的认知激活模式
From me I develop this it's going to work
我这样激活认知并取得了效果
Into the sort of testing and support type environments
这样的方式对这些测试有效且多种环境下依然有效
Ritual is used extensively in military environments
仪式在军事环境中广泛使用
So that's good Valuable
所以这很有价值
The trouble is we then take it to excess
麻烦的是我们接下来过度了
I work for IBM for 7 years
我在IBM工作了7年
I hasten to add I was conscripted I didn't volunteer
我补充一下，我是被征募者非志愿者
It worked out quite well for me I'm still proud of the fact I didn't fill out a timesheet in 7 years that's a World record breath
我在那工作不错。我仍然为我在7年内没有填写时间工时表感到骄傲，这是一个世界纪录的呼吸
It takes a level of defiance which are here even I didn't think I was capable but I managed it
需要一定程度的蔑视它，即使我不认为我有能力，但我可以管理它
And I managed to avoid the school cross country run for 9 years so I think you know that was a slightly better achievement alright
我设法避免学校越野跑了9年. 这是一个稍微大一点的成就
Either way that took me more about bureaucracy than anything else I can remember
无论哪种方式都比我记忆中的其它事情让我更多地了解官僚主义
They take us over we were in Anglo Dutch company called data Sciences we had a flat management hierarchy
他们把我们带到了我们在Anglo荷兰公司，称为数据科学，我们是扁平化的组织结构
Everybody knew everybody else kind of like we got things done and
每个人都认识其他人, 就像我们所有事情都完成了
And then we became part of the world's largest Bureaucracy
然后我们成为世界上最大的官僚机构的一部分
And the first thing they did was to charges for coffee and buying alcohol
他们做的第一件事就是咖啡收费和然后买酒
Now this is completely unreasonable the alcohol coffee cycle
现在完全处于这样的一个循环中了
it is critical for good software development
它对于良好的软件开发至关重要
Nobody should be expected to talk to users without alcohol first
没有人在没有酒精的时候和用户交谈
You don't have to sober up to write the code and then you need even more alcohol
你不必清醒地编写代码，然后你需要更多的酒精
Because users never want what you can prove they asked for
因为用户永远不会想要证明他们所提要求
When you give them the what they asked what they discover they wanted something else instead
当你告诉他们他们所提要求，发现他们想要别的东西替代
I'm going to come back to that later because also architecture is about dealing with an articulated needs
我稍后会再回过头来看，因为架构就是处理明确需求
Not articulated needs
Not articulated needs
That technology capability is progressing faster
技术能力正在加快发展
Than user know what to ask for
比用户知道自己想要什么更快
Yeah and our current models don't actually cope with it
目前的模型实际上并不能应对它
We have to overcome this
我们必须克服这一点
I smuggle the alcohol I kept for my stuff out of the office one night
有天晚上我把办公室里的酒精偷偷带出了办公室
And then we have meetings in hotels which would charge of to meeting space and wouldn't mention the coffee in the alcohol
然后我们在酒店举行会议，这些会议室收费，并且不会提及酒精中的咖啡
So that was fairly easy
所以这很容易
It got worse They banned us for buying food from staff Anybody been in Widnes corporate environments
接下来变得更糟，他们禁止我们在公司环境任何人那购买食物
Yeah no food may be bought for staff it's a waste of money it's the improper reproach
食物不应该从工作人员那购买，这是浪费钱，这是不正当的责备
By now we've learnt you didn't argue with I being bureaucrats on an evidence base
到现在为止，我们已经知道你并没有因为官僚的基本证据而争辩
From the perspective of customer or employee need that wouldn't work
从客户或员工需求的角度来看，这是行不通的
The only thing which occasionally work was the Socratic technique if anybody knows their philosophy
如果有人知道他们的哲学，那么偶尔工作的唯一事情就是苏格拉底式的技巧
It was Socrates did was to ask people questions until they tore themselves apart on there own contradictions
苏格拉底确实是在向人们提出问题，直到他们在自己的矛盾中脱颖而出
It's an extremely enjoyable process you get train to do it in philosophy I enjoyed it thoroughly
这是一个非常令人愉快的过程，你可以通过哲学来训练它，我非常喜欢它
But you always have to remember that eventually the people of Athens get together and decide they had enough for your corrupting the Young
但你总是要记住，当你摧毁他们的年轻人时，雅典人收购了会聚在一起
And vote for you to take hemlock all right so you have to be careful on this one
并投票给你，所以你必须小心这个
Anyway so that's what we did
这些就是我们所做的
So we said ok this is a brilliant move we would never have thought of banning food for staff
这是一个我们永远不会想到禁止员工食物的明智之举
This is one of the benefits of joining IBM
这是加入IBM的好处之一
And then you realise because they look pleased that irony is a deadly weapon
然后你意识到他们看起来很高兴这样的讽刺是一种致命的武器
You can switch on and off with HTML code here inside chats during conference calls
您可以在电话会议期间在聊天内部使用HTML代码打开和关闭
so they actually think with we generally like this
他们实际上认为我们一般都喜欢这样
I said I got a problem
我说我有个问题
Yeah I know  C-level executives that means I only see customers when they're very very angry
我认识C级管理人员，这意味着我只会在他们非常生气的时候看到客户
The high you get promoted
The high you get promoted
The last chance you are of ever having a good relationship with a customer
您与客户建立良好关系的最后机会
Because you're the poor side gets thrown the problems when they finally stop trying to solve It for themselves
因为当他们最终停止尝试为自己解决问题时，面对被抛出的问题你是弱势的一方
And give up the right side in that position
在这种情况下放弃站在正确的一侧
I got called out it's 4 o'clock in the morning we got a Vax cluster down
我早上4点钟就被叫出来了，我们一个Vax集群挂了
Yeah I got three system programmers in and we've only got three  system programmers left in the entire company understand cluster.
我把整个公司懂集群的三个系统程序员全部拉进来了
I'm grateful we still got them
我很感激我们还能抓到他们
We got an emergency service which just has to be up at 9 a.m. in the morning
我们得接到了紧急服务服务，必须在早上9点起床恢复
If we don't have it up we got massive penalty clauses anybody been there with one of those other things
如果我们没有恢复，我们将得到了大量的惩罚，任何人都有在可能在那里有一些东西
I can't do anything at all technically anymore all I can do is get ready to deal with the customer
我在技术上做不了人和事，我能做的就是准备好与客户打交
Stop other managers interfering with the technical people in fact that's my main role to give them the space
我的主要作用是阻止其他经理干扰技术人员，为他们提供空间
And buy them pizza and Coke so they stay awake.  so I can take what do I do if I have to buy them pizza and Co
然后给他们买披萨和可乐，这样他们就能保持清醒. 我做我能做的，如果我需要给他们买披萨和可乐。
They looked really worried and I realise they could have made a mistake so I said I did mean Coca-Cola
他们看起来很担心，我发现他们可能犯了一个错误。 我说我意味着可口可乐
And there was another side relief but I must admit we did start the think about options there don't streamed
还有另一方面的解脱，我们确实开始考虑那些没有排查的选项
And they looked at me and I said well ok we understand that may occasionally necessary tell you what it will make an exception clause in the The rules
他们看着我，我说好了我明白可能偶尔需要在规则中做出什么例外条款
If you get vice presidential approval 48 hours in advance
如果您提前48小时获得VP批准
You can buy food for your staff
你可以为你的员工购买食物
At this point you breathe deeply remember Socratic technique
在这一点上你深深地记得苏格拉底式的技巧
You say god that's brilliant we really would never have thought of that and
你说上帝那太棒了，我们真的永远不会想到这一点
No sarcasm get added to irony as a weapon
没有任何讽刺作为武器
What happens on the extremely rare occasion
在极为罕见的情况会发生什么
When we can't get 48 hours notice for major crisis
当我们无法获得48小时的重大危机通知时
You can tell there is a chart
你可以看那一张图表
And they look worried about points and now you're the Socratic technique is working so they actually made another exception
他们看起来很担心点，现在你的苏格拉底式技术正在发挥作用，所以他们实际上又做了一个例外
Is it OK country general manager approval after the event
活动结束后是否可以获得总经理的批准
Now that is the classic bureaucrat response
现在这是经典的官僚回应
I say yes in a way which means no
我以某种方式说“是”，其实这意味着没有
They really are very good at this
他们真的很擅长这个
You know that means your expenses will disappear into the Southbank there'll never be signed
你知道这意味着你的费用将消失，永远不会签字
And if you complain about it your name will start to appear on the wrong list so right
如果你抱怨它，你的名字就会开始出现在错误的名单上
You don't want to be on those lists out there bad places to be
你不希望在那些不好的名单上出现
So I gather because I would never do this you understand and nobody I know we're never do this but we did hear rumours about friends
So I gather because I would never do this you understand and nobody I know we're never do this but we did hear rumours about friends
equipment ships remotes from our own business units who did this
从我们自己的业务部门远程运送过来
Over tipping London taxi drivers
通过给伦敦出租车司机小费
But if you ever tip a London taxi driver they give you a blank receipt
但如果你给伦敦出租车司机小费，他们会给你一张空白的收据
The blank receipt was then filled out for the amount of money spent on the pizza and Coke
在空白收据填上以已获得审批在的比萨饼和可口可乐花费的金额
A parallel set of books for cat so that you could say to the other people can prove
一套平行的书，以便你向其他人说出可以证明并获得认证
But they haven't wasted company money
但他们没有浪费公司的钱
And the responsible manager took a book bus and to actually playing for the taxi
负责的经理坐了一辆公共汽车实际上是为了打出租车
That became widespread
这变得普遍
I gave this example at the scrum Alliance conference in Berlin 2 years ago
2年前我在柏林的Scrum联盟大会上举了这个例子
Free people from IBM run up to me afterwards
会后IBM的三个人跑过来跟我说话
And said we're still doing that did you invent it
说我们仍然按照你的那个发明在做
And that's 15 years later
这已经过了15年
Last year in Dubai one of them came up and opened his wallet and showed me all the black receipts
去年在迪拜，其中一人上前打开钱包，向我展示了所有的黑色收据
Was collected in case you needed them
收集起来以备不时之需
If you over constrained system which can't be naturally constrained
如果你过度约束一个自身不接受约束的系统
People work around it
人会找到应对之策
And actually if that's a key issue in system design
实际上这是系统设计中的关键漏洞
People will work around the system they won't follow the pattern if it doesn't work for me
如果它对我不友好，人们将在系统中找到不遵循约束的应对之策
So there's nothing wrong with hardly constrained or they provide you don't take it to excess
所以几乎没有约束没有什么不妥，或者不要约束过度
The chaotic system
混沌的系统
In my language is a system without constraints
用我的话说是一个没有约束的系统
or rather without effective constraints
或者没有有效的约束
That means there's no structure to it
这意味着它没有结构
Everything is random
一切都是随机发生
which actually means if it happens accidentally it's a major crisis but it will never last for long
这实际上意味着如果它发生意外这是将是一场重大危机，但它永远不会持续很长时间
If you can deliberately create the conditions you have a hugely powerful tool
如果你可以刻意创造条件，你就拥有了一个非常强大的工具
Where can I get the working on North Korea
我在哪里可以得到朝鲜的工作
Where are we presenting infographics to tens of thousands of people
我们在哪里向成千上万的人展示信息图表
Getting in to interpret them in real time
尝试实时解释它们
Enjoying the Max from the interpretation so we can show out outlier opinions, dominant opinions and various aspects
从解释中得到最大享受，我们能表达不同意见、主流意见及不同角度的意见
The reason we can do that is there is no connection no constraint
我们能做到这一点的原因是没有连接没有约束
Between any of the agents making a decision
在做出决定的任何代理人之间
Yeah if you can actually remove all constraints you can get radical innovation
如果你真的可以去除所有约束，你可以获得激进的创新
So chaos as advantages
所以混沌就成为了优势
it takes a lot of energy to create it
它需要花费很多精力创造它
Most human systems are complex
大多数人类系统都很复杂
That means they have what they call enabling constraints
这意味着他们拥有所谓的启用约束？？？
And the whole point about a complex system
复杂系统的重点
Is it it doesn't have linear causality
它没有线性因果关系
it has dispositionality
它有适应性
It means I can make statements about how it's disposed to evolve
这意味着我能够讲述它如何发展
But I can never say if I do X it will always produce Y result
但我永远不会说如果我做事情X它总会产生结果Y
It's sometimes known as the science of inherent uncertainty
它有时被称为不确定性科学
Is the science of systems in which there is no linear relationship between cause and effect
系统的科学是因果关系，没有线性关系
All that we have is dispositional States
我们所拥有的只是趋势
Now the key thing which goes with this is dependent on what type of system you're in you will manage in a different way
与此相关的关键取决于您所处的系统类型将以不同的方式管理
And
And